we're going to
take a look at the documentation for
ruby's merge method
we'll see that there are two merge
methods
one has a bang or an exclamation mark at
the end
so we're going to write a little bit of
code to see the difference between these
two methods
we've got two hashes on lines one and
two of our
text editor cat and weight
and each of these hashes just has one
key value pair
so let's output the return value of
calling merge on the cat
hash and we'll pass in weight as the
argument
running our code you can see that this
returns a new hash
with both key value pairs so the calling
hash and the hash that was passed in as
an argument
have been merged into one hash with
all key value pairs
we can see that this merge returns a new
array
by then outputting cat
and weight after we invoke this merge
method
you can see that although the merge
method returned
a new array with both key value pairs as
seen on the first line of output
the original hashes cat and weight were
not changed
so this merge the merge without a bang
is not destructive
it simply returns a new hash
now i'm going to comment out this code
and let's demonstrate the use of merge
with a bang
again we'll output the result of
invoking merge
on cat and passing in weight as an
argument
but this time we're invoking the merge
method with a bang
so we see the same output here the
returned hash
includes the key value pairs from both
the calling hash
and the argument hash
let's output cat and weight below this
and now we'll see something a little bit
different
on line two is where we output the cat
hash
you can see that this hash has been
permanently modified or mutated
that's because merge with a bang is a
destructive method
the hash we pass in as an argument
weight
is not modified or mutated however the
calling hash
cat is so the difference here
is that merge without the bank returns a
new hash
merge with the bank is destructive and
mutates the calling hash